Satan also has one son.
Warlock is a horror, fantasy, action film directed by Steve Miner.
In 17th century New England, witch hunter Giles Redferne captures an evil
warlock, but the conjurer eludes death with supernatural help.
Flung into the future, the warlock winds up in the 1980s and
plans to bring about the end of the world.
Redferne follows the enchanter into the modern era and continues his
mission, but runs into trouble in such unfamiliar surroundings.
With the help of a young woman, can Redferne finally defeat the warlock?
Warlock, played by Julian Sands.
Kassandra, played by Lori Singer.
Giles Redferne, played by Richard E. Grant.
Channeler, played by Mary Woronov.
Chas, played by Kevin O'Brien.
Mennonite, played by Richard Kuss.
Warlock is a 1989 American supernatural horror film directed
by Steve Miner and written by David Twohy.
Julian Sands stars as the title character, a son of Satan who travels from the late
17th century to the modern era with the mission of destroying the world.
Lori Singer and Richard E.
Grant co-star as a 20th-century woman and a
17th-century witch-hunter attempting to stop him.
The film was shown internationally in 1989, but did not
receive an American release until January 11, 1991.
It received mixed reviews and grossed $9 million on a $15 million budget.
Two sequels followed, with Sands reprising his role in the first sequel Warlock: The Armageddon
(1993), although both sequels serve as standalone films with no connection to the original.
The film explores themes of witch, magic, cemetery, time travel, aging.
The tone is dark.